groundtruth.com 2019-12-31

# Privacy Policy - GroundTruth - GroundTruth

## Ad Platform Privacy Policy

Effective Date: December 30, 2019

This privacy policy explains how xAd, Inc. dba GroundTruth (“we,” “us,” “our”) and our affiliates and subsidiaries collect, use, and share information via our mobile advertising service and mobile advertising landing pages (“Services”).

* * *

## Overview of GroundTruth’s Services

GroundTruth is a mobile advertising platform specializing in location powered mobile ads. Our Services combine data, technology, and strategy to help advertisers reach the audiences most likely to be interested in their products or services.

If you visit the mobile website or use a mobile application of one of our platform members, that property will have its own privacy policy and practices. You will need to refer to the member’s privacy policy for information about their data collection and use practices.

GroundTruth adheres to the Digital Advertising Alliance’s (“DAA”) self-regulatory principles, the Digital Advertising Alliance Canada’s (“DAAC”) self-regulatory principles, the Internet Advertising Bureau (“IAB”) UK’s Good Practise Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising and the European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance’s (“EDAA”) self-regulatory principles.

### Data Collection & Use

We may collect various types of information from mobile devices using cookies, scripts, web beacons, software development kits (“SDK”), or other similar techniques. These technologies are used to collect digital actions of users that visit and use mobile websites and applications, or interact with ads presented in mobile websites and applications of our platform members. We also receive other data (e.g., demographic information) from third parties or through analytical techniques that we combine with the data we collect or derive through the Services.

The categories of data we collect may include:

  * Digital identifiers, such as device identifiers and IP addresses;
  * Information about the browser and operating system type and version, device type, and other data from or about a mobile device;
  * Precise geolocation data;
  * Postal addresses; and
  * Information about users’ web viewing and application usage activity, including what advertisements are interacted with.

We may collect this data from a variety of sources, including over time across different mobile apps, websites, browsers or devices. We may also receive data related to the location of a mobile device from our platform members and other parties, such as consumer data resellers. We may also receive physical address information from our customers or other third parties, or we may derive address information from other location information we receive or collect from mobile devices.

We may use any of the data we collect and receive for a variety of business purposes including analytics; auditing; research; reporting; attribution; detecting security incidents and illegal, deceptive, or fraudulent activity; service enhancements and other business operations; predicting possible relationships among different browsers and devices; differentiating and/or associating multiple device users as well as associating devices or users with locations such as a household or workplace; frequency capping and other auditing purposes; and in multiple ways to make ads more relevant, such as by inferring potential interests based on web viewing and application use activity for advertising purposes.

For instance, we may use location data for proximity or audience advertising. Proximity advertising uses location and other data to present ads based on a device’s current location. Another example would be using location and other data to create “audiences” – groups of devices that are inferred to share similar interests or other characteristics based on the information we collect – to deliver ads that we believe may be more relevant to those audiences. We consider both proximity and audience advertising to be interest-based advertising as described in this policy. We retain data used for interest-based advertising only as long as we have a legitimate business purpose to retain such data, or as otherwise required by applicable law.  

### Choice

We use data collected across different devices and from non-affiliated websites and applications over time as well as other data described in this policy to provide advertising on behalf of our clients that is relevant to a device’s location and/or interests inferred from this data. This form of advertising is known as interest-based advertising. We may also partner with other ad companies to extend our audiences across different browsers and devices for interest-based advertising purposes.

You may download the DAA’s AppChoices mobile app, or the TRUSTe mobile app, on your iOS or Android device in order to exercise choice regarding the collection of mobile application use activity for interest-based advertising on this device by us and other companies that participate in those choice tools. Links to those applications are below:

Location Data Choice: The DAA’s AppChoices tool can also be used to exercise choice regarding the collection and use of precise location data by GroundTruth for interest-based advertising purposes. iOS and Android users can limit our collection of precise location data from a device by turning location services off through the settings on that device.

If you would like to exercise choice regarding our, and for other third parties that participate in the DAA Choice Page, collection of web viewing data from web browsers for interest-based advertising purposes on this device, [_click here_](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/).

When you make your choices on your browser or device using these choice tools, we will stop collecting and using data from that browser or device for interest-based advertising on it. We will also stop using data collected from that browser or device on other browsers or devices associated with it, and will stop using data collected from those associated browsers, devices, or elsewhere for interest-based advertising on the opted-out browser or device.

Note that electing to opt out from GroundTruth services will not stop advertising from appearing in your browser or applications. It may make the ads you see less relevant to your interests. In addition, note that if you use a different browser or device, erase cookies from your browser, or reset your platform ad identifier, you may need to renew your opt-out choice. In addition, we may still collect data in browsers or apps for non-interest based advertising purposes such as for analytics and reporting purposes, operations, improving our services and frequency capping.

### Data Sharing

We may share the various types of information we collect and infer about devices and users with our affiliates, third party partners and agents for advertisement targeting, audience extension across different browsers and devices, to make and create offers, for other marketing and advertising purposes, to provide reporting to advertisers and clients, to improve our systems and products, and for other research and analytical purposes.

We may also share data with contractors and service providers who work on our behalf. We may disclose data in response to subpoenas, court orders, or other legal process, or to establish or exercise our legal rights and obligations or defend against legal claims. We may also transfer data in the event of an acquisition or merger with another company, including at bankruptcy.

### Children

Our services are not intended for children under the age of 13, and we do not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 13.

* * *

## Website Privacy Policy

Voluntarily Submitted Information on our Websites  
This privacy policy applies to our corporate websites and explains how xAd, Inc. dba GroundTruth (“we,” “us,” “our”) and our affiliates and subsidiaries collect, use, and share information on www.groundtruth.com, or other websites we control that link to this policy (collectively “Website”). By using the Website you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy.

### Information Collection & Use:

#### Personal Information

When you use the Website, you may encounter areas that allow you to voluntarily enter personal information, which includes contact information such as your name, email address, telephone number, and mailing address.

You may provide this information to us when you sign up for our newsletter, request information about products, apply for a job, fill out surveys, or otherwise provide personal information to us.

We may use personal information for, among other things:

  * Internal record keeping and auditing;
  * Communicating with you about site updates and your inquiries, as well as offer products, content, and services that we believe may be of interest to you;
  * Customizing the Website;
  * Verifying customer information; and
  * For purposes disclosed at the time of collection.

If you would prefer not to receive communications from us in the future, please follow the unsubscribe instructions available in each communication.

We may retain your information for as long as necessary to fulfill a legitimate business need, such as to provide you with information or services, comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements.

#### Usage Information

When you browse our Website we may also collect various types of usage information about your browser or device, including, but not limited to, online identifiers such as your IP address and your mobile device identifier, as well as information about your internet activity such as the web pages visited, links clicked, and your operating system and browser type. Such information is used for the purpose of operating, debugging, and improving our Website, analyzing demographic and statistical research about website usage, customizing offers, and to monitor the Website for compliance with our terms of service and the law, to detect security incidents and malicious, deceptive, fraudulent, or illegal activity, as well as other purposes. This usage information may be collected through various technologies, including but not limited to “cookies” when you visit the Website. For more information, please see the “Tracking Technologies” section below.

#### Information Sharing

We will not sell, rent, license, trade or disclose your contact information collected through our Websites to an unaffiliated third party, except with your permission or for circumstances described in this policy. We may share or disclose personal and usage information in certain circumstances, including sharing with:

  * Service providers that perform a business function for us for purposes like CRM management and infrastructure support;
  * Our subsidiaries and affiliates;
  * Entities, such as government agencies, as required by a court order, subpoena, warrant, or when otherwise required by law;
  * Entities as part of a sale or merger of all or part of our business, including at bankruptcy;
  * Third parties for our direct marketing purposes; and
  * Entities to protect our rights and the rights of third parties.

The Website may contain links to third party websites that we do not control, and to which this privacy policy does not apply. We encourage you to read the privacy policy of every website you visit.

#### Security

We follow generally accepted standards to help protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once it is received.

#### Update Personal Information

If you wish to access, update or request deletion of the personal information you have previously provided to us through this website, such as your email or phone number, you may do so by writing us at [requests@groundtruth.com](mailto:requests@groundtruth.com) stating that request. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe.

#### Tracking Technologies

GroundTruth and our partners use cookies or similar technologies to analyze trends, administer the Websites, collect information about use of the Websites, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level, but if you choose to disable cookies, it may limit your use of certain features or functions on our Website or service. To manage Flash cookies, please [_click here_](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html).

We use Google Analytics to better understand how visitors interact with our Websites. This service provides usage information including but not limited to data on where visitors came from, what actions they took on our Websites, and where visitors went when they left our Websites. We use this information to improve your experience when visiting our Websites. Please [_click here_](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites) to learn more about this service and how to opt out of data collection by Google Analytics.

#### Digital Advertising

We may partner with ad networks and other ad serving providers (“Advertising Providers”) who serve ads on behalf of us and others on non-affiliated sites. Some of those ads may be personalized, meaning that they are intended to be relevant to you based on information Advertising Providers collect about your visits to this site and elsewhere on the Internet over time, as well as from various mobile applications you use, across different devices.

You may visit [_www.aboutads.info_](http://www.aboutads.info/) to learn more about this type of advertising and how to opt-out of this type of advertising by companies participating in the Digital Advertising Alliance self-regulatory program. Additionally, if you would like to opt-out of this type of advertising in mobile apps, you can visit here and download the opt-out app for your device.

GroundTruth adheres to the Digital Advertising Alliance’s Self-Regulatory Principles. Note that electing to opt out will not stop advertising from appearing in your browser or applications. It may make the ads you see less relevant to your interests. In addition, note that if you use a different browser or erase cookies from your browser, you may need to renew your opt-out choice. You can also opt out of browser-based interest-based advertising by us and other companies that offer choice by [_clicking here_](https://preferences-mgr.truste.com/), or if located in the European Union you can [_click here_](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices) to make choices with respect to companies integrated in the YourOnlineChoices consumer choice platform.

#### Children

This Website is not intended for the use of children under the age of 13. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13.

* * *

## California Residents

This section contains disclosures required by the California Consumer Privacy Act (“CCPA”) and applies only to “personal information” that is subject to the CCPA. Consumers with disabilities may access this notice by utilizing standard screen readers.

 **Personal Information We Collect, Disclose, and Sell.** We collect the categories of personal information about California consumers identified in the chart below. As further set forth in the chart below, in the past 12 months, we have disclosed and sold California consumers’ personal information to third parties for business or commercial purposes.

Categories of Personal Information| Categories of sources from which information is collected:| Business or commercial purposes for collection, use, and sharing:| Disclosed for business purposes to the following categories of third parties:| Sold to the following categories of third parties:  
---|---|---|---|---  
Personal identifiers (such as first and last name, email address)| Customers (agencies and advertisers);  
Ad inventory supply partners (Publishers);  
Service providers;  
Consumer data resellers; and  
Other third party partners| Marketing;  
Legal compliance;  
Performing services (for us or our service provider) such as account servicing, processing orders and payments;  
and  
Other one-time uses.| Service Providers| This information was not sold in the past 12 months to third parties  
Online identifiers (such as unique online identifiers)| Consumers;  
Customers (agencies and advertisers);  
Ad inventory supply partners (Publishers);  
Service providers;  
Consumer data resellers; and  
Other third party partners| Advertising;  
Marketing;  
Data analytics and insights; Measurement;  
Attribution;  
Reporting and fraud prevention;  
Auditing;  
Legal compliance;  
Detecting and protecting against security incidents, fraud, and illegal activity;  
Debugging;  
Performing services (for us or our service provider) such as account servicing, processing orders and payments;  
Internal research for technological improvement;  
Internal operations;  
Activities to develop, maintain and improve our products and services; and  
Other one-time uses.| Service Providers| Advertising networks;  
Measurement companies;  
Publisher partners;  
Data analytics providers;  
Companies to which we provide our products and services;  
Demographic Information  (such as gender)| Consumers;  
Ad inventory supply partners (Publishers); and  
Consumer data resellers; and  
Other third party partners| Advertising services and advertising products;  
Data analytics and insights;  
Measurement;  
Attribution;  
Reporting and fraud prevention;  
Legal compliance;  
Detecting and protecting against security incidents, fraud, and illegal activity;  
Debugging;  
Performing services (for us or our service provider) such as account servicing, processing orders and payments;  
Internal research for technological improvement;  
Internal operations;  
Activities to develop, maintain and improve our products and services; and  
Other one-time uses.| This information is not disclosed to third parties in the past 12 months.| Advertising networks  
Internet or other electronic network activity information (such as browsing history, search history, interactions with a website, email, application, or advertisement)| Consumers;  
Consumer data resellers; and  
Other third party partners| Advertising services and advertising products;  
Data analytics and insights;  
Measurement;  
Attribution;  
Reporting and fraud prevention;  
Legal compliance;  
Detecting and protecting against security incidents, fraud, and illegal activity;  
Debugging;  
Performing services (for us or our service provider) such as account servicing, processing orders and payments;  
Internal research for technological improvement;  
Internal operations;  
Activities to develop, maintain and improve our products and services; and  
Other one-time uses.| Service Providers| Companies for which we provide advertising services  
Geolocation information| Consumers;  
Customers (agencies and advertisers);  
Ad inventory supply partners (Publishers);  
Service providers;  
Consumer data resellers; and  
Other third party partners| Advertising services and advertising products;  
Data analytics and insights;  
Measurement;  
Attribution;  
Reporting and fraud prevention;  
Legal compliance;  
Detecting and protecting against security incidents, fraud, and illegal activity;  
Debugging;  
Performing services (for us or our service provider) such as account servicing, processing orders and payments;  
Internal research for technological improvement;  
Internal operations;  
Activities to develop, maintain and improve our products and services; and  
Other one-time uses.| Service Providers;  
Analytics providers| Companies for which we provide advertising services  
Inferences drawn from the above information about your predicted characteristics and preferences| Service providers;  
Other third party partners| Advertising services and advertising products;  
Data analytics and insights;  
Measurement;  
Attribution;  
Reporting and fraud prevention;  
Legal compliance;  
Detecting and protecting against security incidents, fraud, and illegal activity;  
Debugging;  
Performing services (for us or our service provider) such as account servicing, processing orders and payments;  
Internal research for technological improvement;  
Internal operations;  
Activities to develop, maintain and improve our products and services; and  
Other one-time uses.| Service Providers| Advertising/marketing companies; Advertising networks; and Companies for which we provide advertising services  
Other information about you that is linked to the personal information above| Consumers;  
Customers (agencies and advertisers);  
Ad inventory supply partners (Publishers);  
Consumer data resellers; and  
Other third party partners| Advertising services and advertising products;  
Data analytics and insights; Measurement;  
Attribution;  
Reporting and fraud prevention;  
Legal compliance;  
Detecting and protecting against security incidents, fraud, and illegal activity;  
Debugging;  
Performing services (for us or our service provider) such as account servicing, processing orders and payments;  
Internal research for technological improvement;  
Internal operations;  
Activities to develop, maintain and improve our products and services; and  
Other one-time uses.| This information is not disclosed to third parties in the past 12 months.| Advertising networks.  
  
 **California Rights.** California residents have certain rights with respect to the personal information collected by businesses. If you are a California resident, you may exercise the following rights regarding your personal information, subject to certain exceptions and limitations:

  * The **right to know** the categories and specific pieces of personal information we collect, use, disclose, and sell about you, the categories of sources from which we collected your personal information, our purposes for collecting or selling your personal information, the categories of your personal information that we have either sold or disclosed for a business purpose, and the categories of third parties with which we have shared personal information;
  * The **right to request that we delete** the personal information we have collected from you or maintain about you.
  * The **right to opt out of our sale(s)** of your personal information. Please note that if you opt out of certain types of sales, we will be unable to provide you with the services that rely on such sales.
  * The **right not to receive discriminatory treatment** for the exercise of the privacy rights conferred by the CCPA.

To exercise any of the above rights, please contact us using the following information and submit the required verifying information, as further described below:

  * Online at [_https://www.groundtruth.com/california-ccpa-rights/_](https://www.groundtruth.com/california-ccpa-rights/)

We may require additional information from you to verify your identity before responding to your request. That verification process can be found _here_. You may designate an authorized agent to make a request on your behalf. To do so please follow the instructions _here_. We do not knowingly sell the personal information of minors under 16 years of age.

* * *

xAd, Inc. dba GroundTruth participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. GroundTruth is committed to subjecting all personal data received from the European Economic Area (EEA), in reliance on the Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable Principles. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield List: [_www.privacyshield.gov/list_](https://www.privacyshield.gov/list).  
GroundTruth’s Website and Ad Platform Privacy Policies, below, describe the types of personal data GroundTruth collects, the types of third parties to which it discloses personal data, and the purposes for which it does so. Residents of the EEA have the right to access the personal information that GroundTruth maintains, and in some cases, may have the right to correct or amend information that is inaccurate or has been processed in violation of the Privacy Shield Principles, to the extent allowed by law. To exercise this right, contact us at [privacy@groundtruth.com](mailto:privacy@groundtruth.com). For information on opting out of interest-based advertising delivered by GroundTruth, please see the Choice section of this Policy below.

GroundTruth is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under the Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. GroundTruth complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EEA, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, GroundTruth is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, GroundTruth may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

Residents of the EEA with inquiries or complaints regarding this Privacy Policy should first contact GroundTruth via the contact information listed in the Website Privacy Policy below. If your privacy concern is not resolved satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at [**www.feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request**](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request). Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield website, you may be entitled to invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

* * *

## Privacy Policy Changes

We may update this privacy policy to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes with respect to our practices relating to your personal information, we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this website prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

#### Contact Us

If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at:

Global Headquarters  
One World Trade  
60th Floor  
New York, NY 10007  

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at [**www.feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request**](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request).

Privacy Policy Last Updated: December 30, 2019
